in this video we're going to talk about
trial balance reports in GP and then
look at how you can print similar
reports in business
Central in my GP system I've printed out
the detail trial balance for a specific
period of time and included all accounts
I can easily see balance information as
well as detailed transactions that were
posted to each
account in addition to the detail trial
balance I've also printed out the
historical age trial balance in
receivables allowing me to easily see
aging information for each of my
customers and drill into any customers
that may have overdue balances that I
need to collect
on now let's look at business Central
and how we can view and print similar
trial balance reports to navigate to the
trial balance reports for general ledger
we will select the search icon and enter
in trial balance in the available
options to select you can see we have
both the trial balance which is similar
to the summary trial balance in GP as
well as the detailed trial
balance in the detail trial balance
report options window I've indicated
that I'd like a new page per GL account
also in the filter area we can filter to
a specific account or range accounts
similar to how you would in
GP now let's preview the report and see
how the information looks
here I can see the balance information
as well as the detailed transactions
posted to the account I can scroll
through the report and see each account
is printed on a new
page now let's look at the summary trial
balance the summary trial balance report
has some different options to select
from I have the ability to compare
values from from last year or if I
configured budgets in business Central I
could compare to the balances that would
have been budgeted below I've selected
to include actual and comparison
balances and display the variance as a
percentage I'm also rounding to the
nearest dollar for Simplicity
sake again I can filter to a specific
range of accounts as well as enter in a
date range for the
report you can see on the summary trial
balance how it Compares this year's
balance to last year as well as
displaying the variance as a
percentage in addition to previewing the
report to the screen I could also send
the report to PDF or word or let's look
like what it would look like if it was
in Excel I'll mark the print to excel
option and preview the report
again in Excel I can easily perform
additional analysis or create different
visuals for the
data next let's look at the Aging report
for
customers in the search field I will
type aged
accounts in the list you can see both
the AP and AR aging reports if I select
the Aging report option for AR similar
to GP I can select a date that I want to
age the report as of and if I want to
age by transaction date or due
date I can also select to print the
report in
detail if I had migrated my customer
class information over as posting groups
I could also filter the report to a
specific customer
class now I can view the Aging
information for each customer and focus
on a specific customer or customers with
balances overdue
and that's a quick look at trial balance
reports in business
Central to learn more about business
Central see the following resources